

NGUYỄN PHƯƠNG PHI

ABOUT ME

I'm a high-motivated person having a passion for logistics. With 3 years experiences in custom brokerage and 2 years working as transportation coordinator, I'm looking for an opportunity to embrace new challenges and enrich my understanding of the industry. With my 5-year experience in Customs Brokerage and Transportation, I believe my experience and skill sets will bring significant contributions to the business growth

CONTACT

Phone

Email

nguyenphuongphi2301@

Address

554/2/12 Nguyen Dinh Chieu Street, Ward 4, District 3, Ho Chi Minh City.

EDUCATION

Marketing University of Finance- Marketing

Time: 2015-2019

Major: Import-Export Customs

SKILLS

- Leadership skills
- Communication & Negotiation skills.
- Teamwork/ Collaboration skills.
- Problem-solving.
- Time management.
- Microsoft skill Computer
 Literacy (MS Office 365).

EXPERIENCE

ITI LOGISTICS Ltd | April 2019 - Dec 2021

Agent - Custom Brokerage

1. Provided end-to-end outbound logistics service for international clients:

- Monitored and traced the status of cargoes from distribution center to client's factory.
- Coordinated with others parties such as suppliers, transportation, order management, sales, freight forwarders, factories, and other service providers.
- Handled customs majors: custom clearance, inspection cargo, additional certificate of origin, tax refund,...
- Had experience to work with several custom department at Custom-Sub Department,
 TCS, SCSC, Cat Lai, SPITC, Transimex, Phuoc Long 3, Giang Nam,...
- Worked with Shipping lines, fowarder to take Delivery order, depot container.
- Registered for specialized testing in Quatest 3, VN Control,...

2. Negotiate with the customs in exceptional situations Achievement:

Solve problem quickly and minimize costs incurred to customers, achieved 100% customer satisfaction.

DB SCHENKERVIETNAM CO., LTD | April 2022 - Now

Distribution Coordinator

1. HSSE

- Monitor and ensure that HSSE policy and Standard Operation Procedure is strictly followed by Logistics Service Providers (LSP)
- Report incidents/ near misses/ unsafe behaviors to Line Manager.

2. Distribution Operations

- Receive Key Account's daily plan from Warehouse and make detailed delivery schedule for each shipments (average 2000 shipments/months).
- Coordinate and monitor LSP's delivery performance from order pick-up to Proof of Delivery (POD) receipt.
- Work with Transportation Management System (TMS) and Telematics to update shipment and service progress to internal and external customers.
- Execute problem-solving during operation, analyze to find the root cause and solutions to improve the service level.
- Monitor and manage revenue and operational costs to ensure monthly P&L is optimized

3. Reporting and KPI

- Monitor and improve processes to ensure operational KPIs are achieved
 - On Time In Full: 99% (vs target 98%)
 - Customer Complaints: 100% (vs target 98%)
 - POD collection: 99% (vs target 98%)

4. Process Improvement

- Contribute to defining and optimizing productivity and efficiency parameters and workflow processes
- LTL Project: Take part in the LTL project, focusing on developing a combined route strategy to maximize the number of trucks utilized while ensuring the highest possible revenue.